DA CHAN **DATA ANALYST**

CONTACT



615-594-8573



dchan159@gmail.com



in www.linkedin.com/in/da-chan52



dchan22 (github.com)



Lebanon, TN

PROFILE

For the past 17 years, I have worked at a smokeless tobacco manufacturing facility. But unfortunately, I am seeing a decline in that field. I am an adaptive person, motivated, initiative-taker, flexible, and good analytical person. Handles pressure from a demanding environment well. Loved the work I did, just needed to change career to a field that is still growing.

PROJECTS

- LOW INCOME AND ELDERLY ASSIST (EXCEL) ANALYZED TAX DATA FOR THE ELDERLY TO FIND WHAT PART OF THE COUNTRY TO NEED/PROVIDE MORE ASSISTANCE
- LAHMAN BASEBALL (SQL) ANALYZED BASEBALL STATISTICS OVER MULTIPLE TABLES. ONE EXAMPLE SCENARIO- WILL TEAMS WITH THE HIGHEST PAYROLL WIN THE WORLD SERIES?
- APP TRADER (SQL) ANALYZED GOOGLE PLAY STORE AND APPLE DATA TO RECOMMEND APPS TO ACQUIRE WITH THE LOWEST ACQUISITION COST AND HIGH PROFIT
- (TEIS)TENNESSEE EARLY INTERVENTION SYSTEM -(PYTHON)

COLLABORATING WITH THE DEPT. OF INTELLECTUAL & DEVELOPMENT DISABILITES. ANALYZED THEIR REFERRAL SYSTEM TO FIND ANY TRENDS WITH THE INCOMING OR **EXITING OF PARTICIPANTS**

SKILLS

- EXCEL
- SQL
- POWER BI
- TABLEAU
- PYTHON
- DOCUMENTATION
- QUALITY PROCEDURES
- JDA SOFTWARE
- LABORATORY INFORMATION
 MANAGEMENT SYSTEM, LIMS
- PROBLEM SOLVING

EDUCATION

DATA ANALYTICS AUGUST 2022 NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

ASSOCIATE OF APPLIED SCIENCE FOR NETWORK SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATION

ITT TECHNICAL INSTITUE – NASHVILLE, TN

EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst Apprentice, NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

May 2022 – present

- Full time intensive bootcamp focusing on analytics and business intelligence.
- Hands-on training using Excel, SQL, Power BI, Tableau, Python
- Project management/ team building using Agile methodology
- Analyzed data using Excel and SQL with PostgreSQL
- Communicate data to stakeholders with dashboards (Power BI and Tableau)
- Training using real data from local companies

Inspector QA MFG II (Flavor Technician), US Smokeless Tobacco - Nashville, TN

August 2017 - May 2022

- Monitored and inspected processes and packaging operations in the manufacturing environment
- Performed moderately complex task and analyses with minimal supervision
- Storing, retrieving, blending, testing, and monitoring ingredients and flavors
- Provided training and guidance to new employees
- Developed, documented, validated new Work Instructions, and improved or updated existing documentation
- Reported monthly inventory and EPA data
- Maintain good Quality documentation and Batch Record Information
- Monitored expiration dates, managing inventories of ingredients/flavors, verification and calibration of equipment used in the process

Miscellaneous Operator, US Smokeless Tobacco - Nashville, TN

APRIL 2005 – AUGUST 2017

- Transportation, Shipping and Receiving
- Forklift, Low Lifts and Machine Operator
- Supply preparation, Assistance to Operators, and Task Supervision
- Pouching, Packing, Sanitation, and Processing